# **CHIA-LIN (Charles) LIU**

2F, No. 6 Heping Street, Hsinchu, Taiwan (R.O.C.) github.com/chialin-liu, charles.ee96@g2.nctu.edu.tw **SUMMARY:** With more than 6 years' experience in IC design house, I am motivated by full stack web technologies and looking forward to contributing my talents on Node.JS/Java Spring

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Hardware Languages/Tools:** Verilog, Perl, Design Compiler, Formal Verification, PowerArtist, Verdi, NC-Verilog, VCS, nLint

**Software Languages/Framework**: JavaScript (ES5/6), HTML5, CSS3, Java, React, Redux, SASS, Webpack, Node.js (Express), Spring family, MongoDB (Mongoose), MySQL, AWS, Redis, Jest

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Senior Digital ASIC Designer, MediaTek Inc., Taiwan

Jan. 2019-Present

- Integrated conditional-access (CA) vendor-specific security IPs to achieve high-end Pay-TV market
- Improved functional test coverage up to 98% on the security IPs in Over-The-Top (OTT) chipsets
- Developed a secret key storage for managing different key generators
- Devoted to researching on low power hardware design to save more than 10% of power consumptions

## Senior, Principal Digital ASIC Designer, MStar Semiconductor Inc., Taiwan

Oct. 2013-Dec. 2018

- Achieved a short-term reward by protecting secret keys from invasive attack in physical place & route
- Succeed to implement an advanced conditional-access chipset certified with a global security lab
- Enhanced hardware simulation platform to save 50% amount of working time by using **Perl**
- Focused on developing a secure crypto environment for set-top box chipsets toward Pay-TV/OTT
- Specialized in DVB MPEG transport stream protection using cryptographic algorithms (AES/TDES)

### **EDUCATION**

# National Chiao Tung University, Hsinchu, Taiwan M.S. in Electronics Engineering, Overall GPA:3.68/4.3 National Chiao Tung University, Hsinchu, Taiwan B.S. in Electronics Engineering, Overall GPA:3.72/4.3

#### **WEB PROJECT**

### Full Stack Web Application https://profile-connection.herokuapp.com/

Feb. 2019–May 2019

- Building a developer's social network with single page application (SPA) with React and React Hooks
- Developing an extensive backend RESTful API with Node.js & Express
- Protecting routes/endpoints with symmetric JSON Web Token (JWT) and verifying API with Postman
- Using **Redux** for managing reducer/action and applying **Redux-thunk** to resolve asynchronous actions
- Building a Responsive Web Design (RWD) with fluid grids and layout types for faster page load

### **Real-Time Chat Room** https://chat-app-liuchialin.herokuapp.com/

June 2019-June 2019

- Designing a bi-directional communication between client and server using Node.JS and Socket.IO
- Users would be notified if a new user enters into or leaves the chat room

# **Spring Web Application**

June 2019–Present

- Creating a web application with Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring Data JPA
- Utilizing Test Driven Development (TDD) with Junit and Mockito
- Leveraging the new **Reactive Types** inside the Spring Framework from the data tier to the web tier